Guide to the Kappa Delta Rho Beta Chapter records, 1913-1988.
Kappa Delta Rho Beta Chapter records, 1913-1988
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Kappa Delta Rho, Beta Chapter records, 1913-1988.
37-4-2130
Fraternity of Kappa Delta Rho. Beta Chapter (Cornell University).
2.5 cubic ft.
Minutes, certificates, correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, and pledge meeting cards.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes, certificates, correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, and pledge meeting cards of Kappa Delta Rho fraternity at Cornell University. Also includes correspondence of William I. Myers and files kept by Horace Shackelton, 1942-1988.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes, certificates, correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, and pledge meeting cards of Kappa Delta Rho fraternity at Cornell University. Also includes correspondence of William I. Myers and files kept by Horace Shackelton, 1942-1988. KDR pin belonging to Robert R. Usher '21.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fraternity of Kappa Delta Rho. Beta Chapter (Cornell University); Myers, William Irving, 1891-1972.; Shackelton, Horace.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
Greek letter societies.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Early Correspondence, Alphabetical by Name
Box 1
Series II. Early Records: Individuals (with photos)
Box 1
Series III. Minutes/House Records
Box 1, 4
Series IV. Initiation Certificates
Box 1
Series V. Miscellaneous Fraternity Items
Box 1, 2, Mapcase Folder 1
Series VI. Bound Volumes
Box 2
Series VII. Photographs
Box 2
Series VIII. Files of Horace Shackelton
Box 3
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Early Correspondence, Alphabetical by Name, 1913-1921
  - A, 1913-1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - D, 1917-1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - E, F, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - G, 1916-1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - H, 1917-1920 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - I-L, 1914-1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - M, 1916-1921 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - N-Q, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - R-S, 1916-1921 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - T, 1917-1920 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - U-Z, 1917-1920 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bonds, 1914, and cancellations, 1918, 1914-1918 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series II. Early Records: Individuals (with photos), 1912-1940
  Collection contains mostly names S-Z, only a few records of letters A-R.
  - Individual Records, A-R, 1912-1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Individual Records, S-V, 1912-1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Individual Records, WA-WI, 1912-1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Individual Records, WI-Z, 1912-1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series III. Minutes/House Records, 1913-1980
  - Minutes, May 1913-June 1915 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, September 1915-October 1922 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, January 1941-May 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Minutes, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Committees, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Minutes, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Propraetor Chapter Evaluation, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1998-2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Portico Repair Bids, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Scholarship Applications, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Corporation Board Meeting, October 12, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - New York State, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Certificate of Incorporation, other legal documents
  - Bylaws, October 23, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - IRS, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Tax-Exempt Status
  - Budgets, 2005-2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Board, August 2006 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Homecoming Board, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Homecoming Annual, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Board, May, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Board, February, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Board, May, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Board, August, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Homecoming Board, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Homecoming Annual, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Board Phone Conference, November, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Board Phone Conference, December, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Board, February, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Board, May, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Board, August, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Board, September, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Annual, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Board, February, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Board, May, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Board, August, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Homecoming Board, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Homecoming Annual, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Board, February, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Board, May, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Board, August, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Homecoming Board, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Homecoming Annual, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Board, February, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Phone Conference, March, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Board, May, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Board, August, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Proxies, September 23, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Kappa Delta Rho USB Drive, May 11, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    Includes Digitized Files, 2005-2012 and a listing of the files.
- Series IV. Initiation certificates, 1925-1980
  - Initiation Certificates, 1925-1929 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1940-1942, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Series V. Miscellaneous Fraternity Items
  - Alumni questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Very Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Handbooks, manuals, directories, songbook (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - ΚΔΡ pin belonging to Robert R. Usher (class of 1921), MU-1514 (Box 1)
  - Copy (1977) of original ( 1909 ) floor plans (Folder 1)
  - Drawing: addition to House, 1964 (Folder 1)
  - Drawing-Alternative plans for addition to the house, 1959-1960 (Folder 1)
- Series VI. Bound volumes, 1922-1959
  - Minutes, Nov. 1922-May 1927 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, Oct. 1927-May 1931 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, Sept. 1931-Jan. 1941 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, Sept. 1953-May 1958 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, Sept. 1958-Jan. 1959 (Box 2)
  - History of Kappa Delta Rho, 1956 (Box 2)
    Signed by Horace Shackelton
- Series VII. Photographs
  - Photographs, 1910s (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1920s (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1930s (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1940s (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1960s (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1970s (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 2000s (Box 2)
- Series VIII: Files of Horace Shackelton, 1942-1988 (Box 3)
  - ΚΔΡ 75th Year Anniversary, September 17, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Includes Speech by Horace Shackelton and Weekend Program
  - ΚΔΡ Library Dedication, March 7, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Includes Beta Briefs, brochure, minutes
  - ΚΔΡ Miscellaneous Files, 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Includes Beta Briefs, Board of Directors minutes
  - ΚΔΡ Financial Data, Letters, etc., 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - ΚΔΡ Financial Data, Letters, etc., 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Includes minutes, membership lists, Proposal for the Installation of an Automatic Fire Detection and Manual Alarm System, letters.
  - ΚΔΡ Guest Book, Quill and Scroll, etc., 1913-1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Includes Quill and Scroll, 1913-1922 Guest Book, Beta Briefs
  - ΚΔΡ Minutes, Circular letters, Purchase Agreement, Finance Statement, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - ΚΔΡ Miscellaneous Files, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Letters, Beta Briefs, Programs, Minutes
  - General Plans and Letters for Reactivating, 1944-1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    See also: Plans of the original 312 Highland Road house before addition (Map Case)
  - ΚΔΡ-H.E. Shackelton Papers, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Includes correspondence and financial records
  - ΚΔΡ Scholarship, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Includes correspondence, financial records, Beta Briefs
  - ΚΔΡ Furnace Data- Amana, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Includes notes, correspondence, proposal
  - ΚΔΡ Miscellaneous Files, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Includes: Article "Mamalutes Colonize", financial records, correspondence, notes
  - ΚΔΡ Miscellaneous Files, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Includes: Correspondence, notes, Beta briefs. See also: alternative plans for the addition to the house (map case)
  - ΚΔΡ Corporation Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - ΚΔΡ Correspondence- Bronstein, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - H.E. Shackelton - KDR, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Includes: correspondence
  - ΚΔΡ Miscellaneous Files, 1952-1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Includes: Notes, correspondence, Beta Briefs,
  - ΚΔΡ Miscellaneous Files, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Includes: Correspondence (Including letter from Norton Electric Company concerning McNiel-Mitchell Multiple Residence Law), Quill and Scroll, Beta Briefs, Invitations
  - ΚΔΡ Miscellaneous Files, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Includes: Correspondence, Newsletter, Quill and Scroll
  - ΚΔΡ Initiation Talk, plans, material, May 20, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - For the Meeting, May 18th, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Includes: Materials pertaining to the sale of the 306 Highland Road chapter house, etc.
  - H.E. Shackelton - ΚΔΡ, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Includes Beta Briefs, correspondence
  - H.E. Shackelton, ΚΔΡ Fraternity, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Includes: Minutes, Correspondence
  - "Return to College" Returns, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Includes: Responses to surveys, correspondence
  - Shackleton- Kappa Delta Rho, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Includes: Minutes, correspondence (in connection with the future of Beta Chapter due to World War 2)
  - ΚΔΡ Insurance, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - ΚΔP Correspondence- Issues with Delta Chapter, July-August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Concerns about the reinstatement of Delta Chapter of Kappa Delta Rho
  - ΚΔΡ- Blum, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Correspondence with Steven B. Blum, Attorney at Law
  - ΚΔΡ Miscellaneous Files, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Includes: Beta Briefs, Quill and Scroll, Minutes, Correspondence, etc.
  - Scholastic Report and Letters, September, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Questionnaire- Replies and Our Replies, October, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 32)